# Aaike Van Roekeghem

Full-stack developer/consultant for websites and applications

#### **Contact Information**

e-mail	aaikevr@gmail.com
website	aaike.ml
Mobile phone	+66 (0)85 669 6707
Address	382 M.4 , Wiang Fang Chiang Mai 50110 Thailand
Skype	aaike.vr
Github	http://github.com/Aaike
LinkedIn	https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=10 403171

# Personal summary

Highly motivated web developer who is able to provide full-stack solutions for websites and applications.

Over 10+ years of professional experience in HTML, CSS and JavaScript based solutions.

Well versed in modern software design principles, practices, and patterns utilizing Aurelia, Angular or other MVC based frameworks.

Always researching new technologies to deliver cutting edge content when needed and cut down development costs for large scale applications. Constant research allows forecasts to be made on how the website industry will change in the near future and how to best prepare an application to be ready for the next generation.

Works well in both team and individual settings and is able to manage a team to work towards a common goal. Being an all-round developer is also ideal for consulting and project management positions as the team can be advised on how to complete a project from start to finish using the correct technologies.

### Education

#### Sint Niklaas Instituut Kortrijk, Belgium (1994-1996) 1st - 2nd degree Social Studies

Social studies at a Hotel and Cooking school to prepare for a degree in Tourism. Studying at a cooking school also gave me basic cooking skills in the French/Belgian culinary arts.

#### Onze Lieve Vrouw van Bijstand Kortrijk Belgium (1996-2000) 3th - 5th degree Tourism

Studied tourism with the idea of going into the tourism industry in Thailand after graduation, most notable areas of studies were History, Tourism, Dutch, English, French and German.

Vrije Technisch Instituut Kortrijk Belgium (1999-2000) 6th degree Web Development

Changed field from Tourism to web development.

# Career history

• Front-end developer @ Dune Enterprises in Brugge Belgium January 2000 - December 2001 (2 years)

Work as a web developer responsible for HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP programming.

Main contact: Jean-Marie De Meester

• **Web Developer** @ The institute for European Studies (Vrije Universiteit Brussels) February 2002 - January 2003 (1 year)

Web developer responsible for creating e-learning material and software.

Main contact: Anthony Antoine

 Web Developer @ Norvell Jefferson Turnhout Belgium March 2003 - January 2005 (2 years)

Frontend development, mostly working with Flash and html, css, javascript for Philips related projects.

• Senior Web Developer @ Norvell Jefferson Turnhout Belgium January 2007 - April 2012 (5 years 4 months)

Front-end development: HTML5, JavaScript (jQuery) and CSS, mostly PSD to html and writing jquery widgets for Philips related projects.

Unfortunately most of the projects created for Philips change on a regular basis and older versions are no longer used at the time of writing, we are also not allowed to use any of these references in our portfolios.

However the pages we created for the Philips websites were much like these for various products:

http://www.philips.co.uk/c/televisions/33092/cat/#/why-philips/intro

http://www.philips.co.uk/c/body-groomers/294301/cat

http://www.philips.co.uk/c/mens-shaving/18672/cat

http://www.philips.co.uk/c/fidelio/301929/cat

These are 2 projects that are still available on the philips website that were created by me and haven't changed yet since:

http://www.connectivityguide.philips.com http://www.ambilightplayer.philips.com

Also worked on plenty of other projects which can be found on the norvell jefferson website: <a href="http://norvelljefferson.com">http://norvelljefferson.com</a>

Main contacts:
Peter Peeters
David Van Ammel
Sebas Bruin
Maarten Bruyninckx
Stijn Debacker

 CEO @ INKI Studios, Chiang Mai Thailand May 2013 - Present

Full-stack web and application development services and consulting for startups.

Projects:

Verbond van Verzekeraars: <a href="http://www.fijndatweverzekerdzijn.nl/">http://www.fijndatweverzekerdzijn.nl/</a>

Wordpress website for a insurance advertisement campaign in the Netherlands.

Dominiques Keuken: <a href="http://dominiqueskeuken.com/">http://dominiqueskeuken.com/</a>

Front-end website implementation for Dominiques keuken.

Gandy Digital: <a href="http://gandydigital.com">http://gandydigital.com</a> Wordpress website for Gandy Digital.

Gooy Angular: <a href="http://gooy.github.io/gooy-angular-demo/">http://gooy.github.io/gooy-angular-demo/</a>

A bootstrapper for Angular that makes it much more modular and capable of writing code in ES6/7, package management and bundling is done with JSPM.

3D Banner creation tool used by retailers of Ad-Wind (<a href="http://www.ad-wind.com">http://www.ad-wind.com</a>)
Main contact: Koen Vandeweyer

Open source contributions to the <u>Aurelia framework</u> including making Aurelia work with <u>plunker templates</u> that are actively used by the community.

## Languages

- **Dutch:** fluent in speaking and reading/writing
- English: fluent in speaking and reading/writing
- French: moderate in speaking and reading/writing
- German: basic in speaking and reading/writing
- Thai: fluent in speaking, very basic to none reading/writing skills

# Volunteering

#### Blood Foundation (<a href="http://www.bloodfoundation.org">http://www.bloodfoundation.org</a>)

Co-founded and helped out with various activities including developing the website, creating flyers/posters, arranging events and teaching web development to buddhist monks.

# **Teaching**

Private tutoring for various web development courses involving HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP and Node mostly to students currently attending high school or university, or web developers looking to upgrade their skill-set.

Most notable student is Artit Seanchompu who studied with me for over a year and now enjoys his web development position with a company based in Chiang Mai who are very pleased with his work and knowledge.

#### Overview of skills

#### Top Skills

These are the skills i am actively working on and and keeping up to date with.

The main focus in the future is to create backends that only provide an oAuth protected REST interface. Other parts of the application are implemented using front-end technologies to communicate with the REST service.

#### Front-end web development

- HTML 5
- CSS
- Javascript
- jQuery
- AngularJS
- React
- Aurelia
- EcmaScript 6/7 using Babel/Traceur
- JSPM
- Gulp / Babel
- Sass, Less, Stylus preprocessors
- Swig, Nunjucks, EJS, DustJS, Dot templates
- Self written stylesheet and widget libraries

#### **Back-end Node.js development**

- Express
- Connect
- KOA
- Meteor
- Sails.js
- Socket.io
- MongoDB
- CouchDB and PouchDB

#### **Back-end PHP development**

- PHP
- Twig
- Doctrine
- MySQL
- PHPCR
- Symfony Framework
- Symfony CMS

#### **Intermediary Skills**

Some technologies and software that i can work with

- Twitter Bootstrap, Zurb Foundation, Materialize.css
- Photoshop (for web design and image processing)
- Illustrator (Vector based drawings)
- InDesign (Creating magazines)
- Android development (native applications)
- PhoneGap for mobile apps
- Flash/Flex
- Wordpress
- Javascript template languages: Handlebars, Jade, Dot, dustjs etc
- Maya (3D modeling and texturing)
- 3D Studio Max (3D modeling and texturing)
- Google Sketchup (3D Architectural visualizations)
- Unity 3D (3D visualizations and games)

#### Other skills

Some technologies and software i have worked with and have a good working knowlegde for but are no longer my main focus or have been replaced with better alternatives.

- Codelgniter
- Yii
- CakePHP
- Yoomla
- Drupal
- KnockoutJS
- Backbone/Marionette
- Mootools
- Kendo UI
- ExtJS
- Webix
- Leap Motion (precision motion detection)
- Oculus Rift (virtual reality simulations)
- Office, Excel, Powerpoint etc...